Hi, my name is Dan Schmidt from the Chinese Martial Arts Center.
Today we're going to showing you proper self defense against the front choke.
Ok, so if somebody chokes you from the front with two hands.
Ok, there's a few very important steps.
First, you want to take your left hand you want to place it on their arm.
Ok, you want to keep your elbow down.
Ok, this is like an anchor.
At the same time with your opposite leg, in this case your right leg, you want to step back, ok, step deep enough so you're shorter than they are.
You want to punch straight to the solar plexis as you twist your hips.
Then take your hand again and palm straight up to the chin.
Ok, from here you can do whatever you want.
Ok, mainly a knee would be best because their groin is right there.
Ok, closest to you.
So he grabs, take the hand, pull down, step back, and twist, hit straight up, then knee right to the groin.
Ok, it's very important as you practice this, you want to get used to grabbing, striking, and twisting all at the same time.
Ok, so he grabs, should be more like this, so you're here, one, and then two, and three.
Ok, it's important that when he grabs, ok you want to grab with one side and step back with the other.
This way I'm on balance.
Ok, so if he tries to wrestle with me and twist, you know, I can move around.
I'm more pliable.
Now, if I stepped back with this side, and he twists, see, I go right off balance.
So you want to incorporate all those together.
So he grabs, and all at once, step here, here.
And then straight with the knee.
That's the proper way to perform self defense against a front choke.